(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
ポルカ・サンシャイン 尾丸ポルカ 生誕祭 2025
Polka Sunshine: Omaru Polka Birthday Celebration 2025
ポルカのおもちゃ箱 尾丸ポルカ 生誕配信 2025
Polka's Toy Box: Omaru Polka Birthday Stream 2025
はーい、皆さん、ようこそ！
Hi, everyone, welcome!
尾丸ポルカ生誕祭2025！
Omaru Polka Birthday Celebration 2025!
はい、あ！ちょうどね、よかった。
Yes, ah! Just in time, perfect.
こちらハッシュタグになっております。
This right here is the hashtag.
#尾丸ポルカ生誕祭2025 で
With #OmaruPolkaBirthdayCelebration2025...
たっ、たっ、たっ、たくさんポストしてね！
P-p-p-post as much as you can!
というわけで、えーとね、
So, well...
今日のライブテーマなんですけど、
today's live theme is...
「おもちゃ箱」みたいな感じをしてます。
like a "toy box."
そして、タイトルは「PuPPet」になっております。
And the title is "PuPPet."
これは…うん、重要な伏線かもしれない。
This... yeah, might be an important foreshadowing.
え！もうね、最初からゲストといっぱい歌っちゃうので、
Whoa! I'll be singing with lots of guests from the start,
もう今はもう何もかもてんやわんや。とにかく、
so everything's chaotic right now. Anyway,
えーと後半にはすっっごい重大発表が山ほどあるから、
well, there are tons of super important announcements later,
最後までぜひぜひ見ていってください！
so please, please watch until the end!
じゃ、えーと最初のゲスト…あ！
Now, the first guest... ah!
姫を連れてきまーす。
I'll bring the Princess along.
どーも！行ってきまーす。楽しみにしてて！
See ya! I'm off. Look forward to it!
半端ならK.O. ふわふわしたいならどうぞ
Half-hearted? Then it's a K.O. If you want a soft life, go ahead
開演準備しちゃおうか
Shall we get ready for the show?
泣いても笑っても愛してね
Love me whether I cry or laugh
ほら Say No
Come on, say no
低音響かせろ
Make the bass resound
踊 作詞：DECO*27 作曲：Giga, TeddyLoid
Odo | Lyrics: DECO*27 | Composition: Giga, TeddyLoid
なんだかな…ってつまんないこともあるでしょう
There are times when things feel kind of... boring
ロンリー論理のノート
Lonely logic notebook
ハンディー本気脱走
Handy, serious escape
やんなっちゃって泥ん
I'm fed up and disappearing
Badご法度だろうが
It might be a bad taboo, but...
溺れて途中で…h！
Drowning halfway... h!
そろそろいっか
It's about time
もっと頑張って
Try harder
アガるまでもっと頑張って
Try harder until you're pumped
繋がろう一人より二人
Let's connect, two's better than one
増えたら安心 心配ないや
More people means peace of mind, no worries
Alright 任せて
Alright, leave it to me
Don't mind 波あり難題
Don't mind, wavy challenges
みんなで乗っちゃえば
If we all jump on board
案外そこっと行っちゃいそう
We might just unexpectedly make it
半端ならK.O. ふわふわしたいならどうぞ
Half-hearted? Then it's a K.O. If you want a soft life, go ahead
開演準備しちゃおうか
Shall we get ready for the show?
泣いても笑っても愛してね
Love me whether I cry or laugh
ほら Say No
Come on, say no
低音響かせろ
Make the bass resound
Yeah 今宵は暗転パーティー
Yeah, tonight's a blackout party
Woah Woah 踊りだせ 踊りだせ
Woah Woah, start dancing, start dancing
孤独殺菌舞い踊れ
Sanitize the loneliness and dance away
痛みまでおシェアで
Sharing even the pain
心でバイバイ Let go
Say bye-bye with your heart, Let go
どんな劣等感だって
Any kind of inferiority complex
即興の血小板で
With improvised platelets
抑え込んで 突っ込んで しまっちゃうでしょ yeah
You'll suppress it, dive in, and put it away, right? yeah
Up and down なテンションで
With up and down tension
まいっちゃってんの相当
You're quite exhausted
ドバっと 噴き出すのは
What gushes out is
本音の独り言
A monologue of true feelings
「別に興味ない」
"I'm not really interested"
「特に関係ない」
"It doesn't particularly matter"
塞ぎ込んで絶頂絶叫へ
Sinking down into a peak scream
合図を奏でて Prrrprrr
Play the signal, Prrrprrr
ほら 集まって 百鬼夜行だ
Look, gather around, it's the Hyakki Yagyō
急いでいこう
Let's hurry
Woah Woah Woah Woah
踊りだせ 踊りだせ 孤独は殺菌マインド
Start dancing, start dancing, Loneliness is a sterilization mind
Woah Woah Woah Woah
痛みまで おシェアで 今宵も点呼パーティだ
Sharing even the pain, Tonight is another roll-call party
Woah Woah Woah Woah
またのお越しを ずっと 待ってる
I'll always be waiting, For your next visit
Woah Woah Woah Woah
次回までお元気で 心でバイバイ Let go
Stay well until next time, Say bye-bye with your heart, Let go
Nan-Nan-Nan-Nan-Ready for my show
OK たませ独壇場 Listen listen
OK, let it be my solo stage, Listen listen
Nan-Nan-Nan-Nan-Ready for my show
傾け
Show off
振り切ろう
Let it loose
Showtime
天地の御成り ほらおいで
The coming of heaven and earth, Come here
宵をコンプリート オールライト He!! yeah yeah yeah yeah
Complete the evening, Alright He!! yeah yeah yeah yeah
だんだんノリノリで超簡単 Bran bran bran!! Pow
Gradually getting into the groove, super easy, Bran bran bran!! Pow
えも言われない Ain't nobody stop
Unspeakable, Ain't nobody stop
全土絢爛豪華
Glitzy and glamorous all over the land
Attention 騒ごうか
Attention, shall we make some noise?
意思表示にも時期衝撃の 声高らか堂々登板
A timely shock even for expressing intention, Stepping up loudly and grandly
もうだらだらは放っておこうぜ
Let's leave the laziness alone
Ayo 繚乱花 御出座した
Ayo, the blooming flowers have arrived
格好つけてるつもりは NO NO
I'm not trying to look cool, NO NO
オトマティックに溢れちゃ本能
Instincts overflowing automatically
宣戦布告の上で はしゃげ華麗
Declare war, then frolic brilliantly
Da rat a tat... WARNING!
Nan-Nan-Nan-Nan-Ready for my show
パンチ効く空気に言祝ぎ Shout it out, Shout it out
Blessing the punchy atmosphere, Shout it out, Shout it out
Nan-Nan-Nan-Nan-Ready for my show
半端ない感情通りに八艘飛び Shout it out, Shout it out
Leaping across ships as my intense feelings dictate, Shout it out, Shout it out
(Ciay na)
Rat tat tat tat tat (Pull up)
(Hey uh, wa wa)
満開 総員一気に飛び切り Jump around
Full bloom, everyone jump around all at once
Look at me now 皮膚を破りそうなほどに跳ねる心臓
Look at me now, heart jumping so hard it might break through the skin
くらい激情的な仕様 (Exotic vox)
Such a passionate specification (Exotic vox)
ミニミニマニモで不退転からのご来光
Sunrise from unyielding determination with eeny, meeny, miny, moe
かくれんぼしてるその気持ち解放
Release those feelings you're playing hide-and-seek with
(理性アディオス) しがみついちゃえ
(Goodbye reason) just cling to it
ジャバラバダビカ あたりにバイバイ
Jabbarabaddabika, bye-bye to the surroundings
野心家 感知するようなジュース
Juice that ambitious people sense
たぶらかす気がカッとなっちゃ嫌
I don't want to get angry with the intention of deceiving
カルマに至って虚無に漂うわ
I'll drift into nothingness reaching karma
ジャバラバダビカ あたりにバイバイ
Jabbarabaddabika, bye-bye to the surroundings
野心家 感知するようなジュース
Juice that ambitious people sense
たぶらかす気がカッとなっちゃ嫌
I don't want to get angry with the intention of deceiving
十色のバタフライ
Ten-colored butterfly
(No escape)
ご存知の通り 喧騒し鼓動に
As you know, by the bustle and heartbeats
絆されても止まれない
Even if tied down I can't stop
衝動に塗装した描いた Daybreak
Painted on impulse, the Daybreak I drew
肺肝通底 狂信狂景
Communicating from the bottom of my heart, fanatical scene
Nan-Nan-Nan-Nan-Ready for my show
異例の危険の 比類なき活気充満
An extraordinary danger, filled with unparalleled vitality
Nan-Nan-Nan-Nan-Ready for my show
いちかばちか嗚呼
Hit or miss, ah
Nan-Nan-Nan-Nan-Nan...
Ready for my show
バンザイ 遊び気にコトブキ
Hurray, enjoy the celebration
Shout it out, Shout it out
Nan-Nan-Nan-Nan-Nan...
Ready for my show
喝采 巻き起こすために Stay
Stay, to raise a round of applause
一切合切 忘れて Shout it out
Forget everything and shout it out
Woah
Aye wah oh oh
右に 左 まとめで Rat a tat tat
Right, left, altogether, rat a tat tat
(Pull up)
思い切り 一気に (Clap Clap Clap)
With all your heart, all at once (Clap Clap Clap)
なにはともあれ ご唱和あれ
Whatever the case, please sing along
Shout it out, Shout it out
Forever glow
記憶と現実の狭間で
Between memory and reality
彷徨い探した 君の居る世界
I wandered searching for the world where you are
白い花を見つける度
Every time I find a white flower
その姿を何度でも
Over and over again
また思い出す
I remember your figure
Forever glow
細い指先さえ
Even your slender fingertips
愛しくて想いが溢れた
Are so dear that my feelings overflowed
声はもう、届かないけど、でも、
My voice no longer reaches you, but still,
心の絆は切れないと信じた
I believed that the bond between our hearts wouldn't break
果て無く続く様な世界で
In a world that seems to go on forever
躓き途方に暮れて行く日々も
Even during days of stumbling and being at a loss
気付けば離れていたようで
It felt as if we had drifted apart
君と同じ道のりを
Along the same path as you
きっと歩んでた
I'm sure I was walking
Forever glow
何故立ち止まったの？
Why did you stop?
悔しさが滲んでいた
Regret was seeping through
声出すのまだ遅くないから
It's not too late to raise your voice
未来へ向かって諦めず走れと
Telling me to run toward the future without giving up
いつも胸に聞こえた
I always heard it in my heart
貴方の歌声
Your singing voice
憧れた強くて、でも、
I yearned for that strength, but,
触れたら消えてしまいそうな
As if it would disappear if I touched it
姿追い求めて
I went in search of that figure
Forever glow
細い指先さえ
Even your slender fingertips
愛しくて想いが溢れた
Are so dear that my feelings overflowed
声はもう、届かないけど、でも、
My voice no longer reaches you, but still,
いつしか運命が重なり合う
One day our fates will overlap
心の絆は切れないと信じた
I believed that the bond between our hearts wouldn't break
夢は見るものじゃない 叶えるものだよ
Dreams aren't just something you see, they're something you make come true
輝きたい衝動に 素直でいよう
Let's be honest with the urge to shine
...なをでいよう
...stay true.
スタートライン！
Start line!
もし君が 立ち止まり 迷う日は
If you ever stop and feel lost,
瞳とじて ココロの声を聞いて
Close your eyes and listen to your heart's voice.
「諦めない」 その言葉が 道になる
“I won't give up,” those words will become your path.
あの日の見た 景色目指して 進もう
Let's head toward the scenery we saw that day.
誰かの真似なんて 退屈なだけさ
Imitating someone else is just plain boring.
ひとりひとり 違うから奇跡
Because we're all different, it's a miracle.
一緒に飛ぼう
Let's fly together.
夢は見るものじゃない 叶えるものだよ
Dreams aren't just for dreaming, they're for making them come true.
輝きたい衝動に 素直でいよう
Let's be true to the impulse to shine.
後悔なんて絶対 君には似合わない
Regret absolutely doesn't suit you.
限りない情熱で 飛び越えていこう
Let's leap over with boundless passion.
スタートライン！
Start line!
さあ 顔あげて
Come on, look up.
チャンスが待ってる！
A chance is waiting!
微笑むペプラム
Smiling peplum
うっとり水玉
Enchanting polka dots
見方を変えたらキュービック
If you change your perspective, it's cubic
新しい自分と 馴染みのアタシと
The new me and the familiar me
おしゃれのパレードは 行く
The fashion parade goes on
fashion check go!
今日は姫カジかな？ (かな)
Is it hime-kaji today? (Maybe)
カラーポップもいいな (いいな)
Color pop is also nice (Nice)
指に触れるカラフル イェイイェイ
Colorful touches on my fingers, yay yay
キュンとワクワクさせるんだ
It makes my heart throb and flutter
ピンクは夢見る自分に
Pink is for the dreaming me
ミドリはまっすぐな自分に
Green is for the straightforward me
無限の遊び場にて
In the infinite playground
万華鏡みたいに変われる
I can change like a kaleidoscope
(red, pink, blue, yellow!)
例えばcuteに
For example, cute
例えばsweetに
For example, sweet
いつもと違う日曜日
A Sunday different from the usual
夢から覚めても おとぎの国へと
Even if I wake up from a dream, to a fairy tale land
おしゃれの旅は続く 続く
The fashion journey continues and continues
(fashion check ful!)
つま先で立って 星に手を のばした1日
Standing on tiptoe, a day spent reaching for the stars
翼の毛布にくるまれて さぁ脚を休めて
Wrapped in a blanket of wings, now rest your legs
疲れているのなんて感じない しあわせで
I don't even feel tired because I'm so happy
瞳は花のように 閉じずに咲いている
My eyes are like flowers, blooming without closing
眠らなきゃ それなのに なんか夢ばかり冴えて
I should sleep, and yet, dreams are just so vivid
そうね胸がおどるの
Yes, my heart is dancing
明日への幕があく
The curtain rises for tomorrow
The curtain opens to tomorrow
（カーテン）
(Curtain)
夜が明ける もうすぐ
The night is breaking, very soon
（時計塔）
(Clock Tower)
頑張るための休息
Rest to do your best
（それもひとつの準備）
(That's also a kind of preparation)
すごく大切なこと
A very important thing
頬にそっとキスする
Gently kissing your cheek
おやすみ チュチュ・バレリーナ
Good night, Chuchu Ballerina
あ、こっちだよ。
Ah, over here.
あー！わー！
Ah! Wow!
あらためて、あ、どうも、こちらに...
Once again, ah, hello, here we are...
はい、素晴らしい方々に来ていただきましたー！
Yes, we have some wonderful guests here today!
みんな言わなきゃ！せーの！
Everyone say it! One, two!
お誕生日おめでとうございまーす！
Happy Birthday!
ありがとうございます！やばい！ピチピチ清楚パワーにやられる...
Thank you so much! Oh my god! I'm being overwhelmed by this fresh, pure power...
ありがとうございます。ありがとうございます。どうも。はい。すごーい、可愛い！
Thank you. Thank you. Hello. Yes. So cute!
あ、こんなに可愛い子たちをね、絶対みんな知ってると思うんだけど...
Ah, these girls are so cute, I'm sure everyone knows them...
もしいたらあれだからちょっと、えっと、自己紹介なんざ、あ、わたくし尾丸ポルカと申します。
But just in case, let's have some self-introductions. Ah, I am Omaru Polka.
あ、よろしくお願いします！
Ah, nice to meet you!
ちょっとじゃあ自己紹介をしていただいてもいいでしょうか？
Could you please introduce yourselves?
もちろんです！では、僭越ながらさせていただきます。
Of course! Well then, if I may.
親愛なる皆様へ、お元気ですか？
To my dear everyone, how are you?
みえる、みえる、スーパーアイドルになってる未来が見える！
I can see it, I can see it, I can see a future where I become a super idol!
姫乃みえるです。よろしくお願いします！
I'm Himeno Mieru. Please treat me well!
はい！マミムメモ、マミム・メェだよ。
Yes! Ma-mi-mu-me-meh, I'm Mamimu Meh.
あくまでも羊じゃないよ。アイドルだよ。
I'm definitely not a sheep. I'm an idol.
お願いします！
Please treat me well!
はい！パリパリパーン！
Yes! Pari-pari-pan!
今日も生まれ変わっていくよ。アイドルの卵、
I'm going to be reborn again today. An idol egg,
わー！パリンだよ！
wow! I'm Parin!
よろしくお願いします！
Please treat me well!
はい！みんなと一緒にショータイム！
Yes! Show time with everyone!
いざ、きらめく瞬間を届けるアイドル、凛堂たいむだよ。
Now, I'm the idol who delivers sparkling moments, Rindou Taimu.
お願いします！
Please treat me well!
あらためまして、アイカツアカデミー配信部からようこそ。お願いします。お願いします。
Once again, welcome from the Aikatsu Academy Streaming Department. Please treat us well. Nice to meet you.
えーと、メドレー歌いました。はい。
Uh, we sang a medley. Yes.
えーと、わたくしが紹介していいんですか？
Uh, should I be the one introducing you?
はい！喜んで！そんな敬語...
Yes! Gladly! Such polite language...
えーと、まず『START DASH SENSATION』、そして『ファッションチェック！』、
Uh, first "START DASH SENSATION", then "Fashion Check!",
そして『チュチュ・バレリーナ』を歌わせていただきました。踊らせていただきました。
and then "Chuchu Ballerina". We sang and danced to them.
慣れないわ、なんかすごい。可愛すぎて。オーラがさ、こっちからくるんにゃ。
I'm not used to this, it's amazing. They're too cute. The aura is coming from over here.
まずあれだね、歌い分けとか一緒に考えたね。
First of all, we thought about the vocal distribution together, didn't we?
そうなんです！みんなで考えた！楽しかったです、あれ！
That's right! We all thought about it together! That was fun!
なんか、なんか、なんとかの歌詞っぽいからそこは君！みたいな。
Like, "this sounds like so-and-so's lyrics, so you take that part!"
一緒に歌うからここはこの誰々と誰々にしようよ、みたいな感じで話した気がする。
I think we talked about, "since we're singing together, let's have this person and that person do this part."
気にして、気にして、あ、注目していただけたらなと思っております。
Please take note, ah, I hope you'll pay attention to it.
ねえ、すごかった。だから、なんかさ、感じたよ、すごい、アカデミーの素晴らしさをあらためて。
Hey, it was amazing. So, I felt it, the greatness of the Academy once again.
可愛い。
So cute.
あの、これからもぜひね、よろしくお願いしたいと思っております。
I hope to continue working with you in the future.
ステージでこうやって喋るだけでさ、あの、ポルカ満足しちゃってるからさ。
Just talking like this on stage, Polka is already satisfied.
なんか、壁になりたいなーって。床になって話し聞いてたいなーっていうぐらいなんなんだよ。
I want to be a wall. I want to be the floor and just listen to you talk, like, what is this?
だめー！みえるも床になっておきます。
No! Mieru will be the floor too.
だめー！自分は天井になる！
No! I'll be the ceiling!
じゃあ照明になろうかな。
Then maybe I'll be the lighting.
空いてるの、空いてるの何？
What's left? What's left?
扉！扉！扉！
Door! Door! Door!
扉返し！扉返し！
Door return! Door return!
扉開けます。
I'm opening the door.
はい、扉開けるらしいです。
Right, apparently she's opening the door.
あのね、なんかさっきさ、マイクさ、持って練習してた時さ、なんかインタビューごっこ...
You know, earlier when we were practicing with the mics, we were playing like an interview...
あ〜見られてたんだ。やだ恥ずかしい。
Ah, you were watching. No, how embarrassing.
緊張ほぐすために。
To relieve the tension.
でもなんかあれ、誰だっけ？お腹すいた...
But who was it? "I'm hungry"...
アイたん？あ、オトたん。あ、水色の方。
Aito-tan? Ah, Oto-tan? Ah, the light blue one.
あ、やばい！やばい！
Ah, oh no! Oh no!
逃げろ！逃げろ！
Run away! Run away!
追われている。何に追われているの？
She's being chased. What's chasing her?
お腹すいた... 今日の気持ちはどうですか？
I'm hungry... How do you feel today?
お腹すいた。
I'm hungry.
やばいバレちゃった。あれ面白かった。
Oops, it got out. That was funny.
水色もお腹すいてますか？
Are you hungry too, Mizuiro?
お腹すいてる？お腹すいてる？お腹すいて... 空いてない！
Hungry? Are you hungry? I'm... NOT hungry!
お腹いっぱいです！
I'm full!
お腹いっぱいなんだ。なんか食べたの？
You're full? Did you eat something?
あ、実は... あのなんか食べてなくて、お腹いっぱいすぎて...
Ah, actually... I haven't eaten, but I'm just too full...
こうして初めて5人で踊れて、嬉しさでお腹いっぱいです！
Being able to dance with the five of us like this, I'm full of happiness!
おー！イェーイ！
Oh! Yay!
そう、前は3人でセンターのさ、4人になってさ、ライムちゃんが来てさ...
Right, before it was three with the center, then it became four when Raimu-chan joined...
すごいなんかその時もポルカも「お〜！」って感じだったしさ。「ライムちゃん来てくれた〜」って思った...
It was amazing, Polka was like "Whoa!" then too. I thought "Raimu-chan is here!"...
これはあの一般的なね、リスナーの感想です。
This is just a general listener's impression.
嬉しいね。またね、新しいデミカツの良さが広がっていったなっていうところで...
It's great. And now, the goodness of Demicatsu has spread even more...
ぜひね、これからポルカもあの宣伝部として頑張りたいから...
I definitely want to do my best as part of the promotion team from now on...
アイカツアカデミー宣伝部！アイカツアカデミー宣伝部！
Aikatsu Academy promotion team! Aikatsu Academy promotion team!
一人で宣伝したいからさ。だのでぜひね、チャンネルの宣伝とかもしあれば... 今、どんどんバンバン...
I want to promote it by myself. So if there's any promotion for the channel... right now, go ahead...
そうですね。我々はですね、4人で『アイカツアカデミー配信部』というチャンネルも持っておりますが...
Right. The four of us have a channel called "Aikatsu Academy Streaming Club", but...
一応ね、個々でも個人でも配信のチャンネルも持っておりますので、お名前とかでバシャバシャバシャって検索していただいたりとか...
We also each have our own personal streaming channels, so if you could search for our names and such...
あとXさんもやっておりますゆえ、そちらの方で今日配信あるよーとかもやっている感じでございますわよね。
Also we're on X. We post about today's streams and stuff there, right?
です！です！です！
That's right! That's right! That's right!
という感じです。で、えっとそうですね。
That's how it is. And, right.
アイカツアカデミー配信部の方では『デミカツ通信』というものを毎週土曜日の20時から生配信で...
On the Aikatsu Academy Streaming Club channel, we do a live stream called "Demikatsu News" every Saturday at 8 PM...
この4人でね、お届けしています。
With the four of us.
そして！もしかして！近々！
And! Perhaps! Soon!
お、お、俺... ポルカさんもお邪魔していいんですか？
Can I... Can Polka-san join too?
えー！ぜひ！
Eh! Of course!
具体的には2月1日にお邪魔します。
Specifically, I'll be joining on February 1st.
逆にね、こうやって遊びに行って、こうやってこっちに来てもらってって、姉妹校みたいですごい嬉しいです。
In return, going there to play and having you come here, it feels like sister schools and I'm very happy.
最近本当にいろんなところでお顔見かけして、年末の去年のところから年始とか... なんかすごいいろんなコラボの幅が広がっていて...
I've been seeing your faces in many places lately, from the end of last year to the beginning of this year... the range of collaborations has really expanded...
あのすごい一リスナーとしてもワクワクとしております。はい。
As a listener myself, I'm very excited. Yes.
なのでみんな、要チェックだぞ！要チェックだぞ！頼むよ！
So everyone, keep a close eye on them! Keep a close eye! Please!
あ、あと俺は？3月3月！
Ah, and what about me? March, March!
ありがとうございました。え、実はですね...
Thank you. Actually...
こちらもアイカツアカデミー配信部のチャンネルの方で3月29日にですね、大型無料単独オンラインライブをやりたいと思っておりますので...
On the Aikatsu Academy Streaming Club channel on March 29th, we are planning to hold a large-scale free solo online live...
ぜひね、見に来てください。アイカツアカデミー配信部のYouTubeチャンネルで！
So please come and watch. On the Aikatsu Academy Streaming Club YouTube channel!
わー！イェーイ！
Whoa! Yay!
すごいぞ見える！めちゃくちゃ完璧だったぞ。さすがだ。うん、可愛い。
Amazing, I can see it! That was absolutely perfect. As expected. Yeah, cute.
じゃあこれからも一緒にいっぱい仲良くしてほしいというわけで... えっと僭越ながらちょっと最後にもう一曲いいですか？
Well, since I want us to continue to be good friends... if I may, could we do one last song?
もちろんです！
Of course!
本当にあれですよ。年末出た新しいあの曲にちょっとお邪魔させていただいてもいいでしょうか？
Seriously, could I join you for that new song that came out at the end of the year?
それではじゃあ一緒に歌って踊りたいと思います。はい。行きますよ。聞いてください。
Then, I'd like for us to sing and dance together. Yes. Here we go. Please listen.
HAPPY REFLECTION!
咲き誇れ未来
Bloom proudly, future
トキメキは
The excitement
響き合うよ
Resonates together
アイカツアカデミー (future)
Aikatsu Academy (future)
夢は恋に似てる
Dreams are like love
(始まりのコドウ)
(The heartbeat of the beginning)
走り出せば止まらないよ
Once you start running, you won't stop
憧れた太陽 まっすぐに見つめる花
A flower staring straight at the sun it admired
小さな祈り 大きな願いになる
A small prayer becomes a big wish
Small prayers become big wishes
遠ざかる入道雲 追いかけて
Chasing the receding thunderheads
雨上がりに
After the rain
輝く
Shining
笑顔を見つけた
I found a smile
幸せ連鎖 1.2.3!
Happiness chain 1.2.3!
煌めく瞬間の 最大風速は今
The maximum wind speed of the sparkling moment is now
反射する光は もっと強く
The reflected light is even stronger
ちから合わせて曇る
Joining forces, even if it's cloudy...
空を晴らしていこう
...let's clear the sky
迷いのない想いの連鎖
A chain of unwavering thoughts
磨かれていくよ
Being polished
アイカツアカデミー！
Aikatsu Academy!
(We make Happy, Happy Reflection Yeah)
Yeah!
虹色の迷路
Rainbow-colored maze
(可能性の回路)
(Circuit of possibilities)
落とし穴は怖いけれど
Pitfalls are scary, but...
ワクワクしてる心を連れていけば
...if you bring your excited heart along
いつでもまた上を目指せるはずでしょう
You should always be able to aim high again
今日も歌えること
Being able to sing today too
なんて奇跡！
What a miracle!
とばしていこう
Let's send it flying
輝く
Shining
(Flash!)
空へ 音の階段登ってLet's GO!
To the sky, climbing the stairs of sound, Let's GO!
満開の笑顔で 繋げるメロディが好き
I love the melody that connects with full-bloom smiles
反射する微笑み もっと大好き！
I love the reflected smiles even more!
瞳にうつるものだけが
Only what's reflected in the eyes...
世界じゃないと知った
...is not the whole world, I learned
わたしらしく 感情を咲かそう
Let's bloom our emotions like ourselves
根をはって生きてくの
Living with deep roots
この場所で
In this place
背伸びして
Stretching
(Fu)
打ちのめされ
Being knocked down
立ち上がれば またへこんで
If I stand up, I'll be depressed again
繰り返す
Repeating
そんな毎日が最高なの
Days like that are the best
Yeah!
刹那的
Momentary
そのひらめき
That inspiration
(Hey)
飛び込む勇気
Courage to jump in
明日を変えるため
To change tomorrow
進め
Go forward
煌めく瞬間の 最大風速は今
The maximum wind speed of the sparkling moment is now
反射する光は もっと強く
The reflected light is even stronger
ちから合わせて曇る
Joining forces, even if it's cloudy...
空を晴らしていこう
...let's clear the sky
迷いのない想いの連鎖
A chain of unwavering thoughts
磨かれていくよ
Being polished
アイカツアカデミー！
Aikatsu Academy!
響き合うよ アイカツアカデミー！
Resonating, Aikatsu Academy!
(We make Happy, Happy Reflection Yeah)
Yeah!
Parade, Parade, Parade!
輝くんだよ 呼び合う声を合図に
We will shine, using the voices calling to each other as a signal
Parade, Parade, Parade!
探しにゆく スタートは何度だって
Going to search, the start can be any number of times
ふわもこだー！
It's FuwaMoco!
おまるん！
Omarun!
ただ 独り言を綴った
I just wrote down my soliloquy
ただ 始まりたくて 走った
I just wanted to start, so I ran
遠く 暗がりに灯った
Lit far away in the darkness
遠く暗がりに灯った
Lit in the distant darkness
それは 眩し過ぎた名前
It's a name that was far too bright
それは 優し過ぎる思い出 もっと
It's a memory that's far too kind, more...
近づけると 手を伸ばした
Reaching out my hand as I get closer
思いがけず 結び合った
Unexpectedly, we were joined together
ほら 今 迷子は “僕等”になった
Look, now the lost child has become "us"
Parade, Parade, Parade! 輝くんだよ
Parade, Parade, Parade! It's going to shine
悔しさも 愛しさも 連れておいで
Bring the regrets and the love along
風、夢、羽 飛び立てるさ
Wind, dreams, wings - we can take flight
ささやかな祈りは 光 終わりなき兆し
Small prayers are light, an endless omen
君を見つけたこと 胸を張れるよ
I can be proud of having found you
ここから これから Our Bright Parade, Parade!
From here, from now on, Our Bright Parade, Parade!
まだ 頼りない予感を
With feelings that are still unreliable
歌おう 恥ずかしくなんてないよ
Let's sing, there's nothing to be ashamed of
誰も解けない イマジナリー
An imaginary world no one can solve
いつかまた逢える おまじない
A lucky charm so we can meet again someday
あの日 ゼロに始まった ストーリー
The story that started at zero that day
数え切れない 言の葉 数えるような想いじゃないさ
Countless words, not the kind of feelings you can count
ほら 今 僕らを一つと呼ぼう
Look, now let's call us one
Parade, Parade, Parade! 美しいんだよ
Parade, Parade, Parade! It's beautiful
許し合える刹那 夜はきらめく
In the moment of mutual forgiveness, the night sparkles
雨、晴れ、カレイド またとない空
Rain, clear skies, a kaleidoscope, a sky like no other
相応しい旅路とは 君と在ることさ
A worthy journey is being with you
君と在ることなんだ
It's being with you
“ただいま”を聞けば “おかえり”って叫ぶよ
If I hear "I'm home," I'll shout "Welcome back"
当たり前じゃないか
Isn't that obvious?
Parade, Parade, Parade! 輝くんだよ 暗がりを満たすのは 君だ 僕だ!
Parade, Parade, Parade! It's going to shine. What fills the darkness is you and me!
Parade, Parade, Parade! 輝くんだよ
Parade, Parade, Parade! It's going to shine
悔しさも 愛しさも 連れておいで
Bring the regrets and the love along
風、夢、羽 飛び立てるさ
Wind, dreams, wings - we can take flight
ささやかな祈りは 光 終わりなき兆し
Small prayers are light, an endless omen
君と飛び込んでゆく 素敵なスタートさ
Jumping in with you is a wonderful start
ここから これから Our Bright Parade, Parade!
From here, from now on, Our Bright Parade, Parade!
Our Bright Parade, Parade!
ふわ、もこ、ありがとう！
Fuwa, Moco, thank you!
おー！
Oh!
かわいい
So cute
Hello Hello Everyone
まもなく On Stage
Soon on stage
ライライ自己暗示さ
Lie-lie self-suggestion
始めよう
Let's begin
ペルソナ
作詞・作曲・編曲：uma vs. モリモリあつし
Persona
Lyrics, Composition, Arrangement: uma vs. Morimori Atsushi
ようこそ PARTY NIGHT
Welcome to PARTY NIGHT
誰かが語る
Someone is telling a story
連日満員御礼 どうぞお気兼ねなく
Full house every day, please feel free
待ってた SHOW TIME
The awaited SHOW TIME
誰かが騙る
Someone is deceiving
どうでもいいような 顔を見せてよ
Show me a face that doesn't matter
偶像捏造 炎上 並べたなら一攫千金
Idol fabrication, controversy, line them up for a quick fortune
ふざけちゃいませんか？
Won't you have some fun?
今 辿り着いた
I've arrived now
憧れの世界
The world I longed for
ここは まるで ペテン師の楽園
It's like a swindler's paradise
吐き気を 飲み込む
Swallowing the nausea
前略 幕が開けた そのオノマトペ
Omission, the curtain has risen, that onomatopoeia
欠片る人形(ヒトガタ)は ピエロに口付けを
The broken dolls, give the clown a kiss
本日大団円 脚本が笑う
A grand finale today, the script is laughing
騙されてくれる あなた達と
With you all who let yourselves be deceived
アタシ 今 ここで 何をしてる？
What am I doing here now?
耳を劈(つんざ)く
Ear-splitting
拍手喝采
Applause and cheers
猿も踊る
Even monkeys dance
...れば人にもなれぬ
...I can't even become a person.
フォーカスされた日常
A focused daily life.
引き金を抱いて
Holding the trigger,
心中するように
as if committing double suicide.
十回、千回、億回
Ten times, a thousand times, a hundred million times,
嘘を重ねて
layering lies.
十回、千回、億回
Ten times, a thousand times, a hundred million times,
瞳をそらして
averting my eyes.
あれなんだっけな あれ？なんだったっけな あれ？
What was that? What was it again?
あたしは誰
Who am I?
もうウンザリした
I've had enough already.
仮面舞踏会
A masquerade ball.
とりとめのない
With rambling...
アイズでお迎え
...eyes welcoming me.
贋作の中
Inside a forgery.
おどけてみせて
Show me you're joking.
おどけてみせてよ
アタシの世界は
My world is...
グルグルグルグルグルグル
...spinning around and around.
回って
Spinning.
全略幕が開けた
Omission, the curtain rose.
そのオノマトペ
That onomatopoeia.
群れがる人形は
The dolls that crowd around are...
ダリアの花束を
...a bouquet of dahlias.
選んでくれた
Choosing for me...
服を着て踊りましょう
...let's put on clothes and dance.
騙されてくれる
You who are deceived,
貴方たちと
along with all of you.
いいよもう
It's fine now.
これが好きだっただけだろ
You just liked this, didn't you?
振り落とせペルソナを
Shake off your persona!
とっくに終わった喜劇は
The comedy that ended long ago...
悲劇と化してなお
...has turned into a tragedy, yet still...
(今日も普通に楽しかったよ)
(Today was fun as usual.)
さあ 括目してくれよ
Now, keep your eyes peeled.
本当の僕は
The real me is...
アタシじゃないから
...not 'me'.
(今日も普通に楽しかったよ)
(Today was fun as usual.)
全略幕が閉じた
Omission, the curtain closed.
そのオノマトペ
That onomatopoeia.
着せ替え人形と
Dress-up dolls and...
輪廻のアンコール
...the encore of reincarnation.
本日大団円
Grand finale today.
脚本が笑う
The script laughs.
どうしようもないよな
It's helpless, isn't it?
どこの誰でもいい
Anyone from anywhere is fine.
調子に乗るなよと
Don't get ahead of yourself.
ただ言ってくれ
Just say it.
そういやユングも
Come to think of it, Jung also...
散々言ってたな
...said it time and again.
もう後戻りは叶わないと
That there's no turning back now.
気付けばそこには一人で
Before I knew it, I was there alone.
フィクションの物語
A fictional story.
というわけで、えー、いつものお馴染みの、
So, with that, uh, with the usual familiar...
えーペルソナで、今私たちはここまで来ましたが。
...Persona, we've come this far.
まず、ゲストたくさん来てくれて、ありがとうございます！
First of all, thank you so much for all the guests coming!
あー、なんかね、今回は、本当に、ここまで駆け抜けちゃったから、
Ah, you know, this time, really, since we've run through everything up to this point...
ま、本当に、あの、デミカツの子たちも来てくれたし、
Well, really, the Demicats kids came as well...
もうこちらとしてはもう満腹、満腹なのですが、
and for me, I'm already full, completely full, but...
こちらで、毎度お馴染みここの喋りと言ったら、
here, when it comes to the usual talk at this point...
告知タイムがあります！
there's announcement time!
グッズ告知、今回も出ます！こちら！
Merchandise announcements, they're coming this time too! Here!
はい、尾丸ポルカ誕生日記念2025！
Yes, Omaru Polka Birthday Celebration 2025!
こちら、あー、なんて可愛いんだ。
This, ah, how cute.
今回はホテルマンがコンセプトになっております。
This time, the concept is a hotelier.
えー、ではでは、グッズを見ていきましょう。
Well then, let's take a look at the goods.
はい、えっと、こちらですね。B2タペストリー「いらっしゃいませ、ようこそお客様」。
Yes, uh, this one. B2 Tapestry "Welcome, customer."
というわけで、ホテルマンの格好をした尾丸ポルカになっております。
So, it's Omaru Polka dressed as a hotelier.
こちら、イラストは茨乃先生に描いていただきました。
The illustration for this was drawn by Itono-sensei.
ちょっとね、いつもと違って、なんか尾丸ポルカもこれパンツスタイルなんでね。
It's a bit different from usual, and Omaru Polka is in a pants style here.
あの、どうですか？ちょっとスッキリ見えますか？
Um, how is it? Do I look a bit more sleek?
あの、君をお迎えしてるっていう感じのシチュエーションになってるので、ぜひね、飾って...
Um, it's a situation where I'm welcoming you, so please, do display it...
「いらっしゃいませ、ようこそお客様!」
"Welcome, dear guest!"
続きとかも、
And with this piece,
あ、ポルカ、ただいまじゃないけど、ホテル来たよーみたいな感じで
you can feel like, "Oh, Polka, I'm home!" or rather, "I've arrived at the hotel."
見ていただければいいかなと思っております。
I hope you enjoy it that way.
一瞬にしてお部屋がホテルに...代わり...
In an instant, your room will... change... into a hotel.
代わりじゃねえな。はい。
Well, not exactly "change." Anyway...
えっと続きまして、2つ目こちら!
Moving on, here's the second item!
ドアプレート風ランダムアクリルキーホルダー
Door Plate Style Random Acrylic Keychains
はい、こちらですね。ドアプレート風ランダムアクリルキーホルダーになっております。
Yes, this is it. These are door plate style random acrylic keychains.
全4種類からランダムに1種類が入っております。
One of four types will be included at random.
イラストは夢ノ内先生に書いていただきました。
The illustrations were done by Yumenouchi-sensei.
なんと、いろんなポルカがいるね。
Wow, there are so many different Polkas!
えっとホテルマンがコンセプトだったさっきのと続いて、
Following the hotel staff concept from earlier,
ホテルの服着たやつと、メイドさんっぽいポルカと、お出かけのポルカと、
we have one in hotel attire, a maid-like Polka, an outing Polka, and...
あ、あいつは死んでんな。
Oh, that one looks exhausted.
「もうだめ」みたいなポルカが入っております。
There's an "I'm done for" Polka in the mix.
はい、えーとこの「もうだめ」みたいなポルカのTシャツがなんとグッズになっております。
And that "I'm done for" Polka is actually on a T-shirt that's also a merchandise item!
3個目のグッズ、こちら!
The third item, here it is!
ポルカと一緒に低気圧と戦うTシャツ
T-shirt for fighting against low pressure with Polka
ポルカと一緒に低気圧と戦うTシャツ!
The T-shirt for fighting against low pressure with Polka!
こちら、ポルカが描きました。はい。
I designed this one myself. Yes.
あの、「低気圧おるか」ということでね、一緒にこれ着て低気圧と抗ったり、
With the pun "Is low pressure here?", wear this to resist the low pressure together,
低気圧に負けたりしましょう。ポルカも着ます。
or just lose to it together. I'll be wearing it too!
一緒に着られたらいいなって思ってます。
I'd be happy if we could wear it together.
というわけで、グッズもう一つ!じゃじゃん!
And so, one more item! Ta-da!
ポルカの顔面ハンガー
Polka's Face Hanger
はい、ポルカの顔面ハンガー!
Yes, Polka's face hanger!
いやね、来ると思うんだよ、顔面ハンガーのブーム。
I really think a face hanger boom is coming.
なんか、ポルカもさっきさ、スタジオでさ、こうやって衣装に着替えてる時にさ、
When I was changing into my costume in the studio earlier,
もう置いちゃおうかなって思ったんだよね。
I thought about just putting it there.
まあ良しとされるかわかんないけれども、みんなもやっぱポルカのこのTシャツも出したし、
I don't know if it's considered good, but since I released this T-shirt too,
ポルカのハンガーも置いて、ちょっと飾っとくっていうのはどうでしょうか。
how about using the Polka hanger to display it?
服もたくさん出てることだし、いろんなアパレルグッズなんかも最近は出てるので、
Since a lot of clothes and apparel goods have been coming out lately,
いいんじゃないでしょうか、顔面ハンガー。
I think this face hanger is a great idea.
2、3個ぐらい買っといてもいいと思います。
Feel free to buy two or three!
はい、それではですね、最後にこちら!
All right, finally, here is this!
ボイス
Voice
グッズ販売単品でこちら、
Available as a standalone item,
「どきどき♡ハラハラなホテルウェルカムボイス」!
the "Pounding & Heart-pumping Hotel Welcome Voice"!
なんか、ホテルと「ほてる」をちょっとかけてるのかな、これ。
Maybe it's a pun on "hotel" and "flushed"?
ちょっとポルカが名前つけたから、ちょっとわかんないです。
I named it myself, so I'm not even sure.
あ、今回も全部ですね、ポルカが名前をつけているので、
Oh, since I named all the items this time as well,
「あ、センスポルカだ」と思ったら、ポルカやったんな、こいつって思っといてください。
if you think, "That's so Polka," then know that I did my best!
で、ここまでがグッズのご紹介で、フルセットを買うとですね、なんと、
That's it for the merchandise intro. If you buy the full set...
数量限定特典でチェキ風ブロマイドカードがついてきます!
a limited-quantity Cheki-style bromide card is included as a bonus!
フルセット購入特典
Full Set Purchase Bonus
で、こちらちょっと説明が大変なんだ。ポルカ初の数量限定でございます。
Now, explaining this is a bit tricky. It's my first ever limited-quantity item.
まずですね、数量限定の方は直筆メッセージと箔押しの複製サイン入りチェキ風ブロマイドカードがついております。
First, the limited-quantity version has a handwritten message and a foil-stamped reproduced signature.
そして特典ボイスは「今日は少し恥ずかしかったボイス」。
And the bonus voice is the "I Was a Bit Embarrassed Today Voice."
でもこれは共通特典なので、ボイスは両方つきます。
But since it's a common bonus, both sets include the voice.
あの、ついてきます。はい。
Yes, it's included. Okay.
で、あの数量限定じゃない、普通の誕生日記念フルセットには、
Then, for the regular Birthday Celebration Full Set that isn't limited quantity...
普通って言ったらあれだよな、あの、すごーいスペシャルな数量限定バージョンと、
Well, calling it "regular" is a bit much. Between the super special limited version and the...
スペシャル記念日フルセットは、えーと、
Special Anniversary Full Set, um...
直筆メッセージはないんですけれども、同じく箔押し複製サインメッセージ入りチェキ風ブロマイドカードがついており、
It doesn't have a handwritten message, but it still has the foil-stamped reproduced signature and message.
さらにこちらにも「今日は少し恥ずかしかったボイス」がついておりますので、
And since the "I Was a Bit Embarrassed Today Voice" is also included,
どちらも甲乙つけがたい内容となっております。
both of them have content that is hard to choose between.
はい、ありがとうございます。
Yes, thank you very much.
そしてですね、あ、これ来ましたよ。最近流行りのじゃない、最近流行りのやつね。
And then, oh, here it is! Not just something trendy, but *the* trendy thing.
はい、こちら!じゃじゃん!
Yes, this! Ta-da!
hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAME PRカード
hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAME PR Card
はい、タレントプレミアムグッズのフルセット特典として、去年から発売されている
Yes, as a full set bonus for the Talent Premium Goods, since its release last year,
hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAMEで使用できるカードが1枚ついています。
one card usable in the hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAME is included.
これ1セットに1枚だからね。
That's one card per set, okay?
えー、オフィシャル...失礼いたしました。
Uh, official... excuse me.
カードはホロライブプロダクションオフィシャルショップで購入された方のみの対象になっております。
The card is only for those who purchase from the Hololive Production Official Shop.
特典につくのはですね、推しをアピールできたりするあの場所に置くやつだな。
The bonus is that one you put in *that* spot to show off your favorite.
キーカード、推しホロメンカードでございます。
It's the Key Card, the "Oshi Holomen Card."
カードの詳細、遊び方についてはホームページをご覧ください。
For card details and how to play, please check the official website.
カードは日本語版のみとなっております。ご了承ください。
Please note that the card is only available in Japanese.
はい、いっぱい告知した。
Whew, that was a lot of announcements.
...と思うじゃん? グッズは以上になるんだけどさ、
...or so you might think. That's all for the merch, but...
もう今回ね、たくさん重大告知っていうものがあるんで。
this time, I have a bunch of major announcements to make.
ポルカね、なかなか重大とか告知とか発表とか使わないんだけど。
I don't usually use words like "major" or "announcement" often,
今回は使っていいかな。
but I think it's okay to use them this time.
まずは1つ目、こちらをどうぞ!
First of all, please take a look at this!
特報
Special News
尾丸ポルカ
Omaru Polka
1stアルバム 発売決定!
1st Album Release Confirmed!
OMARU POLKA - FILMY FUNNY
新曲7曲を含む豪華版アルバムを…
A luxury album including 7 new songs...
【限定特典盤】【通常盤】の2形態にて発売！
Available in 2 editions: Limited Edition and Standard Edition!
本日21:05~ RELEASE!
Released today at 21:05!
はー！出ました！
Hah! It's out!
尾丸ポルカ 1stアルバム『Filmy Funny』、
Omaru Polka's 1st album, 'Filmy Funny,'
2025年1月30日リリースということで、今日だー！やったー！
released on January 30, 2025—which is today! Yay!
こちら、なんとグッズ付き特装版あり。
This one actually has a special edition with goods.
今も見たと思いますが、
As you just saw,
全部に直筆サインがついた完全受注生産にて発売されます。
it'll be a made-to-order release where every copy comes with a hand-signed signature.
ということで、アルバムの現物自体はですね、この後予約開始がされてます。
And so, pre-orders for the physical album itself will start right after this.
で、いや、そんな待てねーよ聞けねーよって人の、方の、ために、
And for those who say, "I can't wait that long to listen,"
デジタルリリースもこの後0時というか24時から日付変わった瞬間だね、されます。
the digital release will also be available at midnight—well, 24:00—the moment the date changes.
ね、えっとですね。先ほど言った直筆サインっていうのは、ええ、限定なんでしょ？と思うあなた。
Now, about that hand-signed signature I mentioned... You're probably thinking, "Wait, isn't that a limited thing?"
いやいやいや、あの、アナザージャケット。
No, no, no. There's something called "Another Jackets."
アナザージャケットというものが入っておりまして、こちら5絵柄があるんですけども、
There are five different designs, and one is included at random.
その中のランダムで1枚、えー、必ず、イラストはランダムなんですけど、1枚必ず直筆のサインがついてきます。
The illustration is random, but one will definitely have a hand-signed signature.
アルバム買った人全員だよ。アルバム買った人全員だからね。全員だよ。すごい。
That's for everyone who buys the album. Every single person who buys it. Everyone. Isn't that amazing?
というわけで、アルバムの内容としては、今年度周年前時にリリースされた『Forever Glow』ほか、
As for the contents of the album, in addition to "Forever Glow" which was released for this year's anniversary,
新たに新曲を7曲！収録しております。
it features seven brand-new songs!
お、そしてですね、えーと、あの、さらに！
Oh, and also... um... there's more!
さらに！さらに！こちらをご覧ください！
More! More! Please take a look at this!
とくほう!!
BREAKING NEWS!!
絡まった糸は解けない 不器用なパペットは今日も踊る
The tangled threads cannot be unraveled. The clumsy puppet dances again today.
みんなのために おどけたい 不器用なパペットは今日も踊る
I want to fool around for everyone's sake. The clumsy puppet dances again today.
本心忘れたフリをして
Pretending to have forgotten my true feelings.
本日21:05~ 尾丸ポルカchにてMV初公開
MV premiere today at 21:05 on Omaru Polka ch
見た？見ました？はい。なんと、この後MVが出ます。新曲だー！
Did you see it? Did you see? Yes! Actually, the MV is coming out after this. It's a new song!
ま、今回のね、あの、ライブのタイトル通り、ま、パペットなんですけれども、
Well, as the title of this live concert suggests, it's called "Puppet,"
これがね伏線回収だったとはみんな気づかなかっただろう。
but I bet nobody realized that was foreshadowing.
も、そしてこの後、今からね、パペット早速ここで歌うのですが、えー、ちょっとドキドキしてます。
And now, I'm going to perform "Puppet" right here. Um, I'm a little nervous.
あの、ちょっと見たと思うんだけど、えー、cosMo@暴走Pさんに作っていただきました。
You probably saw a glimpse of it, but it was created by cosMo@Bousou-P.
で、改めてね、まあこの曲も聴けるということで、アルバムやデジタルリリースもお手に取ったり、えっと、お聞きください。
So, since you can hear this song now, please do check out the album and digital release.
ちょっとあの、ごめ。まじで緊張してるんだ、この曲かっこよすぎて。
Wait, sorry. I'm actually really nervous because this song is just too cool.
というわけでですね、改めて、え、実はパペットを含めて、
So, once again... believe it or not, including "Puppet,"
残りあと2曲になっております！
there are only two songs left!
あ、いい声、いい声、いい声。
Ah, what a great voice, great voice, great voice.
よし、というわけで、残りあと2曲、最後まで盛り上がっていっくぞー！
Alright then, two songs left! Let's keep the energy up until the very end!
絡まった糸は 解けない
The tangled threads cannot be unraveled
不器用なパペットは 今日も踊る
The clumsy puppet dances again today
みんなのために おどけたい
I want to fool around for everyone's sake
不器用なパペットは 今日も踊る
The clumsy puppet dances again today
本心忘れたフリをして
Pretending to have forgotten my true feelings
パペット 作詞・作曲・編曲：cosMo@暴走P
Puppet - Lyrics, Composition, Arrangement: cosMo@Bousou-P
いっくぞー！
Let's go!
くるくるくるくる 踊り踊る
Spinning, spinning, spinning, dancing around
私が舞えば 皆笑顔になる
When I dance, everyone starts smiling
くるくるくるくる 踊り踊る
Spinning, spinning, spinning, dancing around
私もそれが嬉しい
And that makes me happy too
でもでもころころ ころころ 巡り巡る
But, but, round and round, round and round it goes
私の笑顔は 本物なのかな？
Is my smile the real thing?
ころころころころ 巡り巡る
Round and round, round and round it goes
悪い子な思考 隙間這う
Naughty thoughts crawl through the gaps
周りの期待に 応えるための
In order to meet the expectations of others
アン・ドゥ・トロワで
With an un, deux, trois
どうかどうか どうかお願い
Please, please, oh please, I beg you
見捨てないで 嫌わないで ねえ
Don't abandon me, don't hate me, okay?
「本当」は──
The "truth" is—
愛情表現 ヘタクソなまままま
I'm still so clumsy at expressing love
回って 転んで 笑われて
Spinning, falling, being laughed at
きっとこれが 正解な世界！
Surely this is the right world!
間違ってないよね 表情の支配！
I'm not wrong, right? Controlling my expressions!
解錠宣言
Declaration of unlocking
ありのまままま
Just as I am
触って心の
Touch my heart's...
深い部分を
Deepest part
そう言いかけて
About to say so
今日も鍵をかける
Locking it today as well
あっ 重たかったよね ゴメン
Ah, it was heavy, right? Sorry
次は間違えないようにするから
I'll make sure not to make a mistake next time
あっ 重たかったよね ゴメン
Ah, it was heavy, right? Sorry
謝ることしかできなくてごめん
I'm sorry I can only apologize
「ままままって それは本当の
Wait, wait, that's not the real...
私じゃない！ 本当の私を見て!!!」
me! Look at the real me!!!"
ままままって それは本当の
Wait, wait, because that's the real...
私だから！ 本当の私を見て
me! Look at the real me
錯乱 錯乱 取り乱し 錯乱
Confusion, confusion, losing control, confusion
結局正気になって 結局
In the end, becoming sane, in the end...
どんな自分も愛してほしい
I want you to love every part of me
余すことなく全部愛してほしい
I want you to love it all without exception
くるくるくるくる 踊り踊れ
Round and round, dance and dance
私が舞えば皆笑顔になる
When I dance, everyone smiles
くるくるくるくる 踊り踊れ
Round and round, dance and dance
私もそれが嬉しい
That makes me happy too
でも でも でも
But, but, but
誰かの理想を演じるための
To play someone's ideal...
ストップ・アンド・ゴー・ダンス 全部全部全部やるから
Stop and Go Dance, I'll do it all, everything
忘れないで
Don't forget
離れないで
Don't leave me
絡まった糸は解けない
Tangled threads cannot be undone
不器用なパペットは今日も踊る
The clumsy puppet dances today as well
みんなのために動きたい
I want to move for everyone
不器用なパペットは今日も踊る
The clumsy puppet dances today as well
本当の愛を探し求め
Seeking true love
感情表現 バグったまままま
Expression of emotion, staying bugged
焦って事故って落ち込んで
Panicking, failing, and feeling down
感情表現 バグったまままま
Expression of emotion, staying bugged
愛情表現 ヘタクソなまままま
Expression of affection, staying clumsy
焦って転んで笑われて
Panicking, falling, and being laughed at
きっとこれが正解ね世界！
Surely this is the correct answer, world!
間違ってないよね 表情の支配！
It's not wrong, is it? Rule of expressions!
解錠宣言
Declaration of unlocking
ありのまままま
Just as I am
触って心の
Touch my heart's...
深い部分を
Deepest part
そう言いかけて
About to say so
今日も鍵をかける
Locking it today as well
Welcome!
あなたもお出まし
You've arrived too
ポルカの誕生日の最初のお客さま！
The first guest of Polka's birthday!
はーい お待たせいたしました
Hi, thank you for waiting
もうね この曲が最後になりますんで
Well, this song will be the last one
めちゃくちゃ盛り上がっていってくれよな！
So let's get super hyped up!
フッフー！ 久しぶりにこの歌歌うんで
Phew! I'm singing this song after a long time
めちゃくちゃ楽しみになっております！
So I'm really looking forward to it!
もう最初のところでね 声何出そう ちょっと忘れちゃってるんだけど
I've already forgotten what kind of voice to use at the beginning, but...
えっと 絶対笑顔にさせちゃうから
Um, I'll definitely make you smile
付き合ってもらうよ！
So come along with me!
Are you ready?
さあさあ近くにおいで
Come, come, come closer
きっと誰もが仰天
Surely everyone will be amazed
奇想天外なショーの始まりさ
It's the start of a bizarre show
グッと惹かれるでしょ？
You're captivated, aren't you?
おっと 押さないでね
Oops, don't push
それでは準備 OK ですか？
So, are you ready?
愉快な動物たち 玉乗りピエロ
Cheerful animals, ball-riding clowns
ハラハラドキドキしちゃうでしょ
It'll make your heart race, won't it?
真っ赤な輪くぐらせ
Make them jump through the bright red hoop
綱渡りして
Walk the tightrope
ちょっとくらいのドジなんてご愛嬌よ
A little bit of a blunder is just charming
Come on line up!
とっておきのライブ
A special live performance
ボーッとしてないで
Don't just zone out
もっと！ もっと！ 手を叩こう
More! More! Let's clap our hands
ほらほらついておいで
Look, look, follow me
目も回るようなサーカス
A dizzying circus
きっとここだけだよ
I'm sure it's only here
ホログラムみたい
Like a hologram
ギラギラ 奇跡が踊る
Glittering, miracles dance
いつかは世界中を
Someday, the whole world...
世界中を 虜にしちゃうぞ
I'll captivate the whole world
さあ！ 2番！ Let's go!
Now! Second verse! Let's go!
うーん 明日の演目は
Hmm, tomorrow's program...
どうしよっかな 屋根裏で
What should I do? In the attic...
秘密の作戦会議さ
It's a secret strategy meeting
いっぱいの観客席が
The packed audience seats...
アッと驚くような
That'll make them go "Ah!"
とびきりのショーを見せましょう
Let's show them a superb show
思い付いたら
Once I think of it
ジッとしてられない
I can't sit still
座員を引き連れて
Taking the troupe members with me
Let's go ねぇ あれがやりたい！
Let's go! Hey, I want to do that!
これもやりたい！
I want to do this too!
どうして時間って足りないの
Why is there never enough time?
さあ みんなで手拍子 ペンライト
Now, everyone, clap your hands, penlights!
もう声も何でもいいからめちゃくちゃ盛り上がっていってくれ
Voices, anything goes, just get super hyped up!
最後までお願いします！ 行くよ！
Please follow me until the end! Here we go!
ポルカはね 皆が好きです！
Polka loves everyone!
えっ 皆も好きだよね？ 何色かな？
Eh, you love me too, right? What color is it?
ホロライブ最高！
Hololive is the best!
上手くいかなくって
Things don't go well...
空回ってばかりで
And I'm just spinning my wheels...
少し落ち込んじゃう日もあるけれど
There are days when I feel a bit down, but...
見ててね
Keep watching me, okay?
大丈夫！いつまでも
It's okay! Forever...
クヨクヨしてらんないし
I can't stay gloomy...
顔を上げて
Lift your head up...
今日のステージがほら
Look, today's stage is...
ね！待ってるのさ
See! It's waiting for us!
ポルカおるか？
Is Polka here?
じゃあここはポルカ、ポルカのコールで統一でお願いします！
Okay, let's all unite with the "Polka!" "Polka!" call!
ポルカ！おるか！ポルカ！おるか！
Polka! Are you here? Polka! Are you here?
ポルカおるよー！ハイ！
Polka's here! Yes!
ポルカおるよー！
Polka's here!
こっちにもおるよ！
I'm over here, too!
こっちもこっちも！ポルカおるよ！
Over here and there! Polka's here!
ポルカ、みんなのところに、おるよー！
Polka is right there with everyone!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
強く強く願うんだ
Wish strongly, strongly...
どんな夢だって
That no matter what the dream...
きっときっと叶うはず
It will surely, surely come true!
何も怖くない
Nothing is scary...
みんなの声は全部
Everyone's voices are all...
ちゃんと届いてるよ
Reaching me clearly!
さあ新しい次元
Now, to a new dimension...
新しい舞台へ
To a new stage...
もっともっと突き進もう
Let's push forward more and more!
まだまだついておいで
Keep following me for a while longer...
笑い転げちゃうサーカス
This circus that'll make you burst with laughter...
絶対ここだけだよ
Is definitely only found here!
初めての仲間
My very first friends...
景色に心も踊る
My heart dances along with the scenery!
今にも世界中を
Even now, I'll take the whole world...
虜にしちゃうから
And make it fall for me...
目を離しちゃダメだぞ
So don't you dare look away!
今回の誕生日も、楽しい誕生日でした！
This birthday was a fun one, too!
歌っちゃった曲！ありがとうございました！
The songs I sang! Thank you very much!
今年もこの日がきたよ！！
みんなにいーっぱいの「愛」を伝える日！！！
This day has come again this year!!
A day to tell everyone "lots of love"!!!
毎年LOVEを更新中～！
力強い背中をみせるから、たまに横に、たまに正面で
Updating my LOVE every year~!
I'll show you my strong back, so sometimes beside me, sometimes in front of me...
いっぱい分かり合っていこう♡
今日も出会ってくれてありがとう！
Let's understand each other a lot♡
Thank you for meeting me today too!
2025.1.30
尾丸ポルカ
Omaru Polka